fromcoasttocastle.com 2015-03-18

# Privacy Policy - Alamo Rent A Car

***UPDATED***

**Effective Date: 10/02/14**

At Enterprise Holdings, Inc. through our subsidiaries operating under the Alamo Rent A Car brand ( **"Alamo"** ), we respect the privacy of our customers. We have implemented this privacy policy to explain to you how we use and protect personal information we may gather from you when you use this Web Site, our Mobile sites, at our rental locations and from third party sources ( **"Privacy Policy"** ).

In order to complete your reservation, we may need to share your information with certain Alamo locations in the U.S., Canada, Europe, and all Alamo locations in Mexico, the Caribbean, South America, and Asia, which are owned and operated by independent licensees ("Licensees"). These Licensees are not controlled by us or our Affiliate companies and are required to identify themselves as " **An Independent Alamo Car Rental Licensee.** " For these transactions, the Licensee is an independent data controller and maintains its own Privacy Policy in respect to the data that you provide. You are encouraged to check the Privacy Policy of the Licensee that is applicable to your rental transaction.

**By using our Web Site, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your information, as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use our Web Site.**

Alamo has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html)including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [customerservice@Alamo.com](mailto:customerservice@Alamo.com?subject=Alamo%20Privacy%20Policy%20US). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint). The TRUSTe program only covers information that is collected through this Web site.

**WHAT INFORMATION IS COLLECTED**

  * **PERSONAL INFORMATION**

**A. INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE** 

As a general rule, you will not be required to provide personally identifiable information as a condition of browsing our Sites. You may provide us with certain information in connection with a transaction or in your interactions with our Web Sites, mobile sites and at our rental locations. This information may include but is not limited to your:

  * name
  * address
  * telephone numbers
  * email address
  * frequent flyer number
  * driver's license number and expiration date
  * date of birth
  * credit or debit card numbers
  * user name and password
  * membership and corporate ID numbers

We may access location based information from your mobile device while searching for an Alamo location in the area in which you have expressed interest. We do not use this information to specifically locate you for any reason other than to provide you the service. If you do not wish to allow us to use your location information then please do not use the service. If you have allowed us to utilize your location information in the past and wish to revoke the permissions to do so please turn off location services at the device level. Failing to provide requested information will not inhibit your ability to browse the Web site or Mobile site, but it may prevent you from being able to complete certain transactions or receive certain services from us.

  * **INFORMATION COLLECTED AND STORED AUTOMATICALLY**

As part of the standard operation of our Sites, certain information may be automatically provided to our Web servers by your computer. For each visitor to our Site, our Web server automatically recognizes the visitor's domain name or IP address (where possible), but not the visitor's email address. An IP address is a number assigned to your computer when you connect to the Internet. As part of the protocol of the Internet, Web servers can identify your computer by its IP address. In addition, we may collect your browser type and operating system. We collect similar information as part of the standard operation of our mobile site, including mobile device brand and model, mobile operation system and carrier. Except as otherwise explained in this policy, we may combine the information we automatically collect from you (as described above and as described below, under "Cookies & Pixel Tracking") with your personal information in order to tailor our website and enhance your online experience by saving your preferences and/or to help identify site features, advertisements and offers that may be of interest to you.

  * **COOKIES & PIXEL TRACKING**

Cookies are short strings of text sent from a Web server to a Web browser when the browser accesses a Web site or Mobile Site. Cookies may be "session-only" or "persistent." Persistent cookies last for more than one visit and are typically used to allow a visitor to our Web site to personalize their experience.

By adjusting the settings in your browser, you can refuse to accept cookies, give yourself the opportunity to accept or reject cookies, or simply receive notice of when cookies are being placed. Refusing cookies may impinge or block altogether your user experience by eliminating personalization or other features.

In conjunction with these cookies, we may also use pixel tags (also known as "clear gifs," "Web beacons" or "1-by-1gifs") on our Web site and in our advertisements. We may work with our Affiliates (companies related to us) and our service providers to help us track, collect and analyze this information. Pixel tags may be used to collect a variety of information about your visit to our Web site, including the pages you view, the features you use, the links you click and other actions you take.

  * To opt-out of this feature when using our rental sites, please click here. An opt-out cookie will be set, blocking our analytics service provider from collecting your data.

Cookies may also be placed by third parties during your visit to the Web site. Our subsidiaries, affiliates and business partners may use these cookies in connection with their use of pixel tags for online preference marketing purposes (discussed below) or to assist us with some of the previously described functions. We do not control these cookies.

  * **Online Behavior Advertising and California Do not Track Disclosures**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet.  These companies employ cookie and pixel tag technology to measure and improve the effectiveness of ads for their clients These companies may use this information automatically collected about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide targeted ads about goods and services of interest to you, and for online preference marketing purposes. **Our system may not respond to Do Not Track requests or headers from some or all browsers.   To learn more about the use of cookers or other technologies to deliver more relevant advertising and your choices about not having this information used by certain service providers, please click [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). ** Please note that opting out of this practice does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

**HOW COLLECTED INFORMATION IS USED**

We use the information we collect for the following purposes:

  * To assist you with reserving and renting.
  * To conduct other transactions that you request.
  * To service your account or membership with us, respond to your questions and contact you when necessary.
  * To provide you with discounts, coupons, offers and other information and opportunities and services that may be of interest to you. You may receive these offers in advertising that is directed to you via third party sites and media properties, including in social media. You may be able to opt-out of these ads by clicking on an icon in the ad or through the privacy settings in each media property.
  * To assist us in providing better products and services (for example, we may contact you by telephone, mail or email to assist us in evaluating the performance of our staff, to assess the quality of product and service received and to help us improve our Web site, facilities and services).
  * To compile statistics and analysis about our customers' use of our Web site, products and services, which statistics are only used to enable us to provide better customer service, products, features and functionality to you and other customers in the future.
  * To help us to operate, maintain and improve our systems and Sites.
  * To allow you to modify or cancel a reservation.

In certain areas of our Sites, we provide you the ability to enter your friend's name and email address in order for Alamo to send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit this Website. Alamo stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. We may combine the information that you submit to us with information related to your transactions with us, such as rental location and vehicle type, as well as with information we receive about you from credit reporting agencies and other data providers who assist us in processing requests, maintaining our data and optimizing our marketing and other services. This Privacy Policy applies to data collected via our websites and mobile sites, in connection with any transaction and at our rental locations. If the same information about you is also gathered from other sources with different privacy policies, Alamo may elect, in its sole discretion, to treat such information in accordance with the privacy policy that least restricts our use and disclosure of such information.

We attempt to retain information we collect for commercially reasonable periods of time or in accordance with specific policies or as required by law to be used for statistical, marketing, archiving, and other analytical purposes. Information collected for a specified purpose will only be used for that purpose and, after a reasonable period of time, will no longer be actively stored when that purpose has been fulfilled. Inactive data may, however, continue to be used for statistical, marketing, archiving, and other analytical purposes.

**_WE WILL USE YOUR INFORMATION IN THE COUNTRY IN WHICH YOU MAKE A BOOKING. PLEASE BE AWARE THAT, UNLESS PROHIBITED BY LAW, YOUR USE AND/OR CONTINUED USE OF THIS WEB SITE SIGNIFIES YOUR EXPRESS CONSENT THAT ALL INFORMATION THAT ALL INFORMATION THAT WE PROCESS MAY BE TRANSFERRED TO OR STORED ON SERVERS AND PROCESSED OUTSIDE THE COUNTRY OF YOUR RESIDENCE, INCLUDING THE UNITED STATES._**

**WITH WHOM THE INFORMATION MAY BE SHARED**

We may disclose the information we collect from and about you to our subsidiaries and affiliates. Our affiliates and our subsidiary employees in our IT, marketing, operations and customer service divisions may use your information, as described in this policy. To update your marketing preferences please see the "CORRECTING OR CHANGING YOUR INFORMATION/CONTACTING ALAMO" section below. We may also disclose this information to third parties: ((1) when required by law, (2) in response to legal process, (iii) without legal process in response to a request from law enforcement relating to a criminal investigation; (3) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, or the public; (4) to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit damage that we may sustain, or (5) to enforce the terms of any rental agreement or our website’s terms and conditions; (6) to our licensees and their licensees or franchisees, and/or third parties, subject to confidentiality agreements as appropriate, for administrative, technical support or other business purposes as necessary to facilitate our transactions with you, to submit email communications to you on our behalf, to process your credit card, conduct analytics services, or to maintain and improve our services; (7) to your frequent flyer or other rewards program provider; or (8) otherwise with your consent. We may disclose your personal information to third-party service providers including a payment processor to bill you for goods or services, an email provider or media agency to send email and other communications to you on our behalf and the provider of our live chat feature in order to offer you customer service, among others. These service providers may be located in a country different from your country of residence, such as the United States or European Union member country. These service providers are contractually required to maintain the confidentiality and security of your information. However, your information may be accessible to U.S. or EU authorities in accordance with applicable laws.

Alamo or its Affiliates may sell or buy other businesses or entities. In such transactions, personal information may be one of the transferred business assets. Also, in the event that Alamo or substantially all of its assets are acquired, your personal information may be one of the transferred assets. You will be notified via email or prominent notice on our Web site or Mobile sites for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

We may also share aggregated or de-identified information about our customers with our adverting and marketing partners, and third party media properties, including social media sites to allow them to send targeted advertising messages on our behalf. With your prior notice and consent, we may share your name and email address with our co-branded partners and affiliates in order to provide the services you have requested and for marketing purposes. If you wish to stop receiving promotional communications from these third parties, please contact the third party.

**TESTIMONIALS**

We may post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our web sites which may contain personally identifiable information. We will obtain your consent via email prior to posting the testimonial. To request the removal of your testimonial, please contact us through one of the methods listed below.

**LINKED SITES**

Our Web site may contain links to other Web sites (such as those of our marketing partners or advertisers), which may have privacy policies that differ from our own. We are not responsible for the activities and practices that take place on these Web sites. Accordingly, we recommend that you review the privacy policy posted on any Web site that you may access through our Web site.

**SOCIAL MEDIA WIDGETS**

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook and Twitter buttons. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**CHILDREN'S PRIVACY**

This Web site is not directed to, and Alamo does not knowingly collect personal information from, children under the age of 13. We recommend that parents actively participate in their children's use of the Internet.

**CHOICES YOU CAN MAKE ABOUT YOUR INFORMATION**

We give you a number of choices about the collection, use and distribution of your information. For example, you must affirmatively request to receive email advertisements from us, our Affiliates and/or business partners concerning information about special offers, promotions and new features, products and services. Every Alamo email advertisement will provide you with the opportunity to remove yourself from our email list. You may choose to opt back in to our email advertisements at any time, in which your most recent action will prevail. We will give you an opportunity to opt-out of the gathering of your personally identifiable information, specific uses of your personally identifiable information and any marketing promotions in accordance with the procedures set out in the section below, " **Correcting or Changing Your Information.** "

**CORRECTING OR CHANGING YOUR INFORMATION/CONTACTING ALAMO**

We are very concerned about the accuracy, currency and completeness of the information we collect and make efforts we deem appropriate to ensure that the information we have is accurate and up-to-date. In addition to the options provided to you in this policy, if you wish to review, amend, correct, update or delete personally identifiable information we have collected about you or limit how we use it contact us at the information provided below. Please also contact us if you have any questions about privacy on our Web site. You may contact us via email at [customerservice@Alamo.com](mailto:customerservice@Alamo.com?subject=Alamo%20Privacy%20Policy%20US), and we will attend to your request and make any necessary revisions. If you prefer, country specific contact information is listed below. We will respond to your access request within 30 days.

We reserve the right not to allow access to your information if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is prohibited by law or if the rights of another individual might be violated.

**SECURITY PROCEDURES**

We are very concerned with the security of your personally identifiable information and try to provide secure transmission of your information from your PC to our servers. For certain transactions on certain of our Web sites, we may use Secured Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to secure the transfer of information. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be absolutely secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information transmitted over the Internet. Once we receive your information, we take steps that we believe are reasonably appropriate to protect its security, both internally and from outsiders, from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction, and to ensure the integrity of the data we collect. We use a combination of technological, physical, administrative and policy methods as well as organizational controls and non-disclosure or confidentiality agreements as we deem appropriate to protect this data.

If you have a user name and password for any of the features on our Web site, you have the responsibility of keeping your password secret. You should not reveal your password to anyone. We will not ask you in an unsolicited telephone call or email for your password. In addition, you should take reasonable precautions when using a computer that is not your own or in a public setting.

**CHANGES IN TERMS**

We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by means of this site (or as otherwise deemed appropriate) prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**SAFE HARBOR**

Alamo complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Alamo has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Alamo’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

**PRIVACY CONTACTS:**

Alamo Rent A Car, National Contact Center Customer Care Department, 8420 St. John Industrial Drive, St. Louis, MO 63114, (877) 858-3884.
